Andrew Halsey

Battle Ground, WA (707) 580-2861

andrewjohnhalsey@gmail.com

DESIRED POSITION: Transmission System Operator

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

A highly motivated and experienced eight-year Navy veteran serving as a commissioning agent performing testing and inspections on various types of critical facilities. Currently working as a mechanical commissioning engineer, working with various confidential cloud computing clients around the country. Equally capable of working as a team member or individually to identify and solve problems in critical facilities equipment. Other key skills include:

Leadership

Communication

• Maintenance Planning

- Technical Inspector
- Functionality Testing
- Training Manager

EXPERIENCE:

Rubicon Technical Services

November 2019 – Present

- Performed a variety of scripted functional tests on systems in critical facilities
- Areas of testing include: Evaporative cooling equipment, refrigeration units, exhaust fans, building automation systems, industrial water systems, and other systems as requested by the client.
- Ensured proper communication between myself, the client, and the equipment vendors to track, troubleshoot, and resolve issues.
- Worked with clients to develop testing scripts to meet the needs of their individual applications in accordance with all applicable requirements.
- Prepare detailed reports upon completion of commissioning to provide the clients with documentation of the rigorous testing process, and to certify that all equipment meets the necessary standards for reliability and redundancy

US Navy, USS Santa Fe, Pearl Harbor, HI

January 2018 – November 2019

- Served as the Leading Engineering Laboratory Technician, leading a team of six junior technicians in the sampling and maintenance of boiler water, condensate, and reactor plant chemistry onboard a nuclear submarine.
- Responsible for providing training at the operator and supervisor levels to approximately 50 personnel in the areas of, chemistry theory, sampling requirements, analytical techniques, response to chemistry casualties, and standards for radiological maintenance.

- Responsible for ensuring that samples were obtained per established frequencies, that operating parameters for plant chemistry are understood, and that upon identifying operating issues, the proper corrective measures were implemented.
- Worked with personnel to ensure proper chemical safety and handling processes, as well as developing an overall culture of safety in plant operations.
- Communicate across all plant departments to provide support for maintenance, where it would have an effect on plant chemistry or the radiological status of the plant.
- Stood watch as a propulsion plant supervisor, leading a team of 10 highly skilled operators to ensure propulsion and electrical power were maintained at all times in a nuclear power plant.

US Navy, USS Santa Fe, Pearl Harbor, HI:

January 2014 – January 2018

- As an Engineering Laboratory Technician, I was responsible for the operation and maintenance of all mechanical and chemistry equipment, to include: demineralized water systems, chemical injection equipment, analytical equipment, turbines, pumps, valves, and air compressors
- When necessary, I created formal procedures for the performance of infrequent maintenance items where no procedure previously existed. These procedures usually involved compiling requirements from multiple different sources to ensure that all regulations were adhered to. Additionally, I was responsible for creating effecting danger tagging for all maintenance procedures.
- Performed sampling and analysis of boiler water, condensate, and reactor plant chemistry and performed chemical additions as necessary to maintain chemistry within operating parameters. Additionally, performed trend analysis of all chemistry data to provide operational recommendations based on the status of plant chemistry.
- As the divisional maintenance supervisor, I oversaw the implementation of our computerized maintenance management system.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

• Certified Associate in Project Management

Quality Assurance Inspector Course

• Operational Water Chemistry and Radiological Controls

• Engineering Laboratory Technician C School

• Nuclear Power Training Unit Charleston

Nuclear Power School

Nuclear Field A School

• Recruit Training Command, Great Lakes Illinois

• Vanden High School: Vacaville, CA

ECD: November 2020

May 2016

November 2014

August 2013-November 2013

February 2013- August 2013

April 2012-October 2012

September 2011-January 2012

July 2011 - September 2011

June 2010